Roberto M. L. Costa

Full Stack Developer

Roberto Costa

São Paulo, Brazil https://betocostadev.github.io/

+55 (11) 98211-2009 robertomarx@gmail.com

https://github.com/betocostadev https://www.linkedin.com/in/robertomcosta/

Background

With a working background in sales but a big passion for technology and programming, in 2018 I decided to follow my passion and dedicate my full time to study Full Stack Development. Back then, I was very familiar with technology (using MS-DOS as a kid) but haven't really written any code. Now I can say I learned a lot about JavaScript, ES6, Git, Node, Express, MongoDB and I am learning React. Although I still have no working experience in the field, I can safely say that I can develop web applications and work with databases.

Skills

Full Stack Web / Software development (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6, Node.js, SASS, MongoDB and Testing (Jest).

Responsive Design (Responsive Images, Media Queries, Flexbox, CSS Grid).

Frameworks (Bootstrap, Mongoose, and Express.js).

NoSQL Database (MongoDB).

Others:

Build Tools (Gulp), Version Control (Git, Github Flow), Website performance (DOM manipulation, image techniques, etc), Design (Figma, Gimp, Inkscape, Blender, Photoshop).

Office Apps (Microsoft Office, Google Apps).

Experience

Trader / Self-employed

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017, São Paulo

Worked as a stock trader learning and trading every day. I started with stock options and later decided to learn more about digital coins. Traded Bitcoin and Litecoin.

Hardware Seller / Self-employed

Jan 2013 - Dec 2015, São Paulo

Computer parts selling using the internet (Mercado Livre). Consulting and selling products.

Sales Specialist / IBM

Feb 2009 - Jun 2011, São Paulo

Design and sales of IBM solutions to fulfill client's needs. System X servers, storage, maintenance, and IBM's software. An end-to-end process from understanding the client's needs to the final implementation of the project. Working with telephone, email, and web contacts with Brazilian and international clients.

Sales Support / IBM

Sep 2007 - Feb 2009, São Paulo

Sales support to sellers and clients, proposal elaboration, documents verification, logistics. End-to-end sales process.

Education

Front-End Web Developer / Udacity Nanodegree

2018, Online

The course was focused on building the student skills in Responsive design, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and GitHub.

Finance Associate Degree / Universidade Anhembi Morumbi

2016, São Paulo

Finance and financial management services

In its routine, the Technologist in Financial Management applies methods, techniques and economic-financial concepts in the decision-making processes, always starting from economic feasibility studies, with the objective of optimizing investments and fundraising.

Courses

The Complete React Developer in 2019 with Redux, Hooks, and GraphQL (Udemy) - Studying

The Complete Node.js Course (Udemy) - 2019

Become a Front-End Web Developer (LinkedIn) - 2019

Learning Linux Command Line (LinkedIn) - 2019

Learning MongoDB (LinkedIn) - 2019

Agile Foundations (LinkedIn) - 2019

Figma for UX Design (LinkedIn) - 2019

SASS Essential Training (LinkedIn) - 2019

UX Foundations: Accessibility (LinkedIn) - 2019

User Experience for Web Designers (LinkedIn) - 2019

JavaScript Fundamentals (Microsoft MVA) - 2018

Create HTML5 Apps with jQuery Jump Start (Microsoft MVA) – 2018

HTML5 & CSS3 Fundamentals: Development for Absolute Beginners (Microsoft MVA) - 2018

Introduction to Logic and Computational Thinking (Microsoft MVA) – 2018

Responsive Websites with Bootstrap 3 (Pluralsight) - 2018

Design to Development (Pluralsight) - 2018

HTML5 Fundamentals (Pluralsight) - 2018

An Introduction to Design (Pluralsight) - 2018

Learning Software Development (Microsoft MVA) - 2017

Software Development Fundamentals (Microsoft MVA) – 2017

Learn How to Learn (Coursera) - 2017

Business Management Fundamentals (USP – VEDUCA) – 2016

Design Thinking (Laureate International) - 2015

Time Management (Laureate International) – 2015

Distance Education (Laureate International) - 2015

Personal Finances and Stocks (BM&F Bovespa - Veduca) - 2015

Macromedia Web Design Studio MX (Senac) - 2005

Languages

Portuguese-Native

English – Advanced